Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine. And today we're talking about some very interesting stories.
我是Catherine。今天我们聊一些非常有趣的故事。
We're going to learn some words for stories or tales. But specifically, what kind of stories,
我们要学习一些关于故事或传说的词汇。但具体来说，是哪种故事呢，
Marco?
Marco？
They're popular stories that you hear maybe through emails or maybe in your town there's
就是那些你可能通过邮件听到的流行故事，或者在你镇上流传的
some particular story about maybe a ghost or many different things that they're kind
一些特别的故事，比如关于鬼魂或各种不同的事情，它们有点
of hard to believe but that happened a long time ago and people still talk about today.
难以置信，但发生在很久以前，人们至今还在谈论。
And they're scary.
而且它们很吓人。
Yeah, they're kind of scary.
是啊，有点吓人。
So let's listen to today's dialogue, hear some interesting stories. And when we come
那么我们来听今天的对话，听听一些有趣的故事。等我们
back, we'll be talking more about what these words and phrases mean.
回来，再进一步讨论这些词汇和短语的含义。
Have you read all these crazy things that are going on around the world?
你读过世界各地发生的那些疯狂事吗？
What do you mean?
你指的是什么？
I was reading about how some people get tricked or drugged in their hotel rooms and have their
我读到有些人如何在酒店房间里被欺骗或下药，然后他们的
organs removed. Then they're sold on the black market.
器官被摘除，再在黑市上卖掉。
Don't tell me you actually believe all that. Don't be so gullible. They are just urban
别告诉我你真信这些。别这么容易上当。那只是都市
legends. They're just stories people make up to scare you.
传说。不过是人们编出来吓唬你的故事。
Well, I was also reading about how some popular songs have subliminal or even satanic messages
嗯，我还读到有些流行歌曲如果倒着播放，会包含潜意识甚至撒旦的
if you play them backwards. Can you believe that?
信息。你能相信吗？
You really think an artist or songwriter is going to go through the trouble of putting
你真以为一个艺术家或词曲作者会费劲去把
subliminal or satanic messages in a song? Don't be so naive.
歌曲里隐藏潜意识信息或撒旦信息？别这么天真了。
Well maybe you are right. But how about the story about how KFC has rows of headless
嗯，也许你说得对。但那个关于肯德基有一排排无头鸡的故事呢？
chickens which are super grown in order to get bigger chickens faster?
那些为了更快地得到更大的鸡而超级生长的鸡？
Sounds a bit too far-fetched to be true, don't you think?
听起来有点太牵强了，不像是真的，你不觉得吗？
All right, we're back. So let's take a look at Language Takeaway.
好了，我们回来了。现在来看看“语言要点”部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So here on Language Takeaway today, we have some words that will help us understand the
今天在“语言小贴士”环节，我们有一些词汇能帮助我们理解
dialogue. The first word is drugged. So I was reading about how some people get drugged
对话。第一个词是“drugged”。所以我正在读关于有些人如何被下药的内容。
in their hotel rooms.
在他们的酒店房间里。
That's right. So if you get drugged, it means that someone gave you some drugs in order
没错。所以如果你被下药了，意思就是有人故意给你下了药。
to make you sleepy or in order for you to not remember what happened.
让你犯困，或者让你不记得发生了什么。
All right. So he was drugged means someone gave him a drug, something that made him go
好的。所以“他被下药了”意思是有人给他吃了某种药物，让他失去意识。
to sleep.
睡觉。
Right. And it's not necessarily always a bad thing because obviously if you go to the hospital,
对。而且这也不一定是坏事，因为显然如果你去医院的话，
the doctor may drug you in order to, you know, so you don't feel so much pain or something.
医生可能会给你用药，你知道的，这样你就不会感到那么疼了。
Exactly. If you're in an accident, you're in a lot of pain, the doctor drugs you so
没错。如果你出了事故，疼得厉害，医生会给你用药。
you don't feel that pain.
你感觉不到那种疼痛。
That's right.
没错。
All right. So he was drugged. This person is drugged. And then what happens?
好的。所以他被下药了。这个人被下了药。然后发生了什么？
Well, his organs were removed.
嗯，他的器官被摘除了。
All right. So organ, an organ is a noun. It's a thing. Those are actually the things that
好的。所以器官，器官是一个名词，它是一个东西。这些实际上是
are inside our body.
我们身体内部的东西。
Right. So your heart, liver, your pancreas, kidneys, etc.
对。比如你的心脏、肝脏、胰腺、肾脏等等。
These are all organs. And this is basically the category for the part of the body. It's
这些都是器官。这基本上是对身体部位的一个分类。它指的是
anything really inside your body that has a function.
你身体内部任何有功能的东西。
Okay. So this is supposedly this story is that people, you know, usually tourists, they
好的。所以据说这个故事是，人们，你知道，通常是游客，
get tricked or drugged and then they get their organs removed.
他们会被骗或下药，然后器官被摘除。
Now what kind of a story is this, Marco? Because it's not just a normal story.
这是什么故事啊，Marco？因为它不只是一个普通的故事。
Right. All of these stories that we saw in the dialogue are called urban legends.
对。我们在对话中看到的这些故事都叫都市传说。
Okay. Urban has to do with cities, right? Legend is a story that may or may not be true.
好的。都市和城市有关，对吧？传说是一个可能真实也可能不真实的故事。
That's right.
没错。
It comes from a long time ago.
它来自很久以前。
So an urban legend is actually a story that is probably not true that you hear from other
所以都市传说实际上是一个可能不真实的故事，你从其他人那里听来的，
people like your friends.
比如你的朋友。
That's right. So usually most of these stories fall under this category. You know, they're
对。所以通常这些故事大多属于这一类。你知道，它们是
urban legends. You don't really know if they're true, but people say it happened to a friend
都市传说。你不太确定它们是否真实，但人们说它发生在他们一个朋友身上，
of theirs from a long time ago or stuff like that.
很久以前的朋友或类似的事情。
Exactly. So a friend of a friend of a friend of mine told me that in hotels, sometimes
正是。所以我朋友的朋友的朋友告诉我，在酒店里，有时
they take your organs. Well, obviously that's not right.
他们会摘取你的器官。嗯，显然那是不对的。
Right. Right. All right. So after that, we have two great adjectives for describing people
对。对。好的。在那之后，我们有两个很好的形容词来描述人。
who like to believe stories like this. What are those two adjectives?
谁喜欢相信这样的故事。那两个形容词是什么？
Well, we have the adjective to be gullible and to be naive.
嗯，我们有形容词“易上当的”和“天真的”。
All right. So they're a little bit different. To be gullible means to believe everything
好的。所以它们有点不同。“易上当的”意思是相信别人告诉你的
that people tell you.
一切。
Right. So if you're gullible, you pretty much believe anything you see or you hear.
对。所以如果你易上当，你几乎会相信你看到或听到的任何东西。
Yeah. So maybe your friend says, did you know Michael Jordan is coming to the office tomorrow?
是的。比如你朋友说，你知道吗，迈克尔·乔丹明天要来办公室？
Right. And you believe it, then you're very, very gullible.
对。然后你信了，那你就是非常非常易上当。
Very gullible. You believe what people tell you. But naive is similar.
非常易上当。你相信别人告诉你的话。但“天真的”类似。
It's similar, but I guess it has a little bit of a different meaning in the sense that
类似，但我觉得在某种意义上有点不同，因为
you're not, it's not that you're so gullible, but you wholeheartedly trust people. So you're
你不是那么易上当，而是全心全意信任别人。所以你
naive, you're innocent.
天真，你单纯。
You're innocent. Maybe you don't have a lot of life experience. So you trust people and
你单纯。也许你没什么生活经验。所以你信任别人，
you can call a person naive. You say, well, he's very naive about these kinds of things.
你可以说一个人天真。你说，嗯，他对这类事情很天真。
I guess that's the main key, right? Or the main point is that you don't really have too
我想这就是关键，对吧？或者主要点是，你没有太多
much life experience. So that's why you're naive.
生活经验。所以这就是你天真的原因。
That's right. And just be careful because gullible and naive are things that we say
没错。但要小心，因为“易上当的”和“天真的”是我们用来
about people, but they're not nice things. They're not compliments.
形容人的词，但它们不是好话。它们不是赞美。
Right. So you shouldn't really say it to someone directly like in the dialogue.
对。所以你不应该像对话里那样直接对别人说。
Exactly. Maybe as a joke, but not seriously.
没错。也许当玩笑说，但不能当真。
Okay. So we have the great adjectives way to describe people. And lastly, we also have
好的。所以我们有很好的形容词来描述人。最后，我们还有
something else that how to describe the situation. Maybe it's too farfetched. It's too difficult
还有别的什么能描述这种情况。也许这太牵强了。太难
to believe.
让人相信了。
So farfetched, this is a great word. It means basically that something is very difficult
太牵强了，这个词很棒。它基本上意思是某件事很难
to believe. Like you say, for example, the story about Michael Jordan. Michael Jordan
让人相信。就像你说的，比如关于迈克尔·乔丹的故事。迈克尔·乔丹
is coming tomorrow. You say, oh, that's pretty farfetched. I don't really think that could
明天要来。你会说，哦，那太牵强了。我真的不觉得那可能
happen.
发生。
Right. So something that is farfetched is difficult to happen or very, very unlikely
对。所以牵强的事情就是很难发生或者非常、非常不可能
to happen.
发生。
Very unlikely.
非常不可能。
Okay. So very good. We saw five key words there. Let's take a break and listen to the
好的。很好。我们看到了五个关键词。让我们休息一下，再听一遍
dialogue again.
对话。
Have you read all these crazy things that are going on around the world?
你读过世界上发生的所有这些疯狂的事情吗？
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
I was reading about how some people get tricked or drugged in their hotel rooms and have their
我读到过有些人如何在酒店房间里被骗或下药，然后他们的
organs removed. Then they're sold on the black market.
器官被摘除。然后它们被在黑市上出售。
Don't tell me you actually believe all that. Don't be so gullible. They are just urban
别告诉我你真的相信那些。别这么容易上当。那只是都市
legends. They're just stories people make up to scare you.
传说。只是人们编出来吓唬你的故事。
Well, I was also reading about how some popular songs have subliminal or even satanic messages
嗯，我还读到过一些流行歌曲如果倒着播放，会有潜意识甚至撒旦的
if you play them backwards. Can you believe that?
信息。你能相信吗？
You really think an artist or songwriter is going to go through the trouble of putting
你真的认为一个艺术家或词曲作者会费心在歌曲里放
subliminal or satanic messages in a song? Don't be so naive.
潜意识或撒旦的信息？别这么天真。
Well maybe you are right, but how about the story about how KFC has rows of headless chickens
嗯，也许你是对的，但关于肯德基有一排排无头鸡的故事呢？
which are super grown in order to get bigger chickens faster?
这些鸡被超级培育，以便更快地得到更大的鸡？
Sounds a bit too farfetched to be true, don't you think?
听起来有点太牵强，不像是真的，你不觉得吗？
All right, let's take a look now at a couple of phrases on Fluency Builder.
好了，现在让我们看看流畅度构建器中的几个短语。
Now in Fluency Builder today we're going to start out with the story about organs, this
今天在流畅度构建器中，我们将从关于器官的故事开始，这个
urban legend. Now what happens when the organ is taken, the story says that it's sold on
都市传说。故事说当器官被取走后，它被在黑市上
the black market.
出售。
That's right. So you probably hear this in the news or a lot of places, the black market
没错。所以你可能会在新闻或很多地方听到这个，黑市
basically. It's not really a physical place, but it's where things are sold illegally.
基本上。它不是一个真正的地方，而是东西被非法出售的地方。
So guns, organs, stuff like that.
比如枪支、器官之类的东西。
Exactly. So the black market, like you say, is not a place you can go to. It's an idea.
正是。所以黑市，就像你说的，不是一个你可以去的地方。它是一个概念。
And it's basically anything that's illegal that's being sold. Like guns are often sold
它基本上是指任何被非法出售的东西。比如枪支经常在
in the black market.
黑市上出售。
That's right.
没错。
Sometimes stolen cars are sold in the black market. Also organs can be sold in the black
有时被盗的汽车也在黑市上出售。器官也可以在黑市上
market. And this is a serious problem because obviously all of this is illegal.
出售。这是一个严重的问题，因为显然所有这些都是非法的。
That's right. So the black market is where all this happens. Now moving on to the next
没错。所以黑市就是这一切发生的地方。现在继续下一个
urban legend that we actually didn't really talk about too much is how many people believe
都市传说，我们实际上没有太多讨论的是，有多少人相信
that popular songs have subliminal or satanic messages in them.
流行歌曲中有潜意识或撒旦的信息。
All right. So let's take a look at the word subliminal first. We all know what a message
好的。让我们先看看“潜意识”这个词。我们都知道信息是什么，
is, right? It's something that's told to us. But a subliminal message is something that
对吧？它是告诉我们的东西。但潜意识信息是
is told to us without us knowing.
在我们不知情的情况下告诉我们的东西。
That's right.
没错。
So it goes into your mind, but you don't even know it. So it's something that a lot of people
所以它进入你的大脑，但你甚至不知道。所以这是很多人
believe in because they think that marketing people or big businesses are trying to control
相信的东西，因为他们认为营销人员或大企业试图控制
our behavior.
我们的行为。
That's right.
没错。
So I could say very quietly, Marco, buy me dinner.
所以我可以非常小声地说，马可，请我吃晚饭。
And that's a subliminal message.
那就是一个潜意识信息。
Marco says, hey, I was thinking about getting everyone dinner tonight. And then that's basically
马可说，嘿，我在想今晚请大家吃晚饭。那基本上就是
a way to control your actions. And so whether or not this is possible, that's another discussion.
一种控制你行为的方式。至于这是否可能，那是另一个讨论。
That's another discussion.
那是另一个讨论。
But so, yeah, that's basically what a lot of people say that some TV commercials or
但所以，是的，那基本上就是很多人说的，一些电视广告或
ads have these subliminal messages that are trying to convince you or persuade you into
广告有这些潜意识信息，试图说服你或劝诱你
maybe consuming that product.
去消费那个产品。
Exactly. But they're a little bit different from satanic messages.
正是。但它们和撒旦信息有点不同。
That's right. So that's basically dealing with Satan or the devil.
没错。那基本上是与撒旦或魔鬼有关。
That's right. So the idea that there are satanic messages means that they're messages about
没错。所以有撒旦信息的想法意味着它们是关于
the devil, about how maybe God does not exist or like, you know, that you should do evil,
魔鬼的信息，关于也许上帝不存在，或者，你知道，你应该做邪恶的事，
not good. So they're very dark and very kind of angry messages.
而不是好事。所以它们是非常黑暗和有点愤怒的信息。
I think they talk about, for example, I'm not sure which song it is, but like by Ozzy
我想他们谈到，比如，我不确定是哪首歌，但像奥兹·奥斯本
Osbourne that if you play it backwards, supposedly there's this message that says, you know,
的歌，如果倒着播放，据说有这样一个信息说，你知道，
worship the devil and stuff like that. So that's where these urban legends come from.
崇拜魔鬼之类的东西。所以这就是这些都市传说的来源。
But obviously it's either coincidence or not true.
但显然要么是巧合，要么不是真的。
Right. That's right. So we've got these messages that are also an urban legend. But the final
对。没错。所以我们有这些信息，也是一个都市传说。但最后一个
one is about KFC. So KFC would be Kentucky Fried Chicken. And what is the legend? The
是关于肯德基的。所以肯德基就是肯塔基炸鸡。传说是什么？传说
legend is about their food.
是关于他们的食物。
That's right. They say that they don't really have real chickens. Well, they take chickens
没错。他们说他们并没有真正的鸡。嗯，他们拿鸡
and they just super grow them. The chickens are super grown in order for them to get bigger
然后只是超级培育它们。这些鸡被超级培育，以便它们变得更大
and faster. And that's basically that they don't even really have heads. They just have
更快。那基本上就是它们甚至没有头。它们只有
some hoses that go into their bodies and feed them. And in four weeks you have a chicken.
一些管子进入它们的身体喂它们。四个星期你就得到一只鸡。
That's disgusting. That's disgusting. The idea is super grown chickens. And so they're
真恶心。真恶心。这个想法就是超级培育的鸡。所以它们
basically they're not real chickens.
基本上不是真正的鸡。
Right. That's what the legend says is that they're not. I mean, they really are, but
对。传说就是这么说的，它们不是。我的意思是，它们确实是，但
they're not like naturally grown. You know, usually a chicken takes three months to grow
它们不是自然生长的。你知道，通常一只鸡需要三个月才能长大
or something.
或类似的时间。
Yeah. All right. That's disgusting. I don't want to talk about that. But the idea of super
是的。好吧。真恶心。我不想谈那个。但超级培育的想法
growing is like using chemicals to do something that's not natural.
就像用化学物质做不自然的事情。
That's right. That's right. Chemicals or hormones and stuff. So that's they use it, for example,
没错。没错。化学物质或激素之类的东西。所以他们用这个，比如，
on plants. You can super grow a plant by adding fertilizer and vitamins and stuff to the soil
在植物上。你可以通过向土壤中添加肥料和维生素之类的东西来超级培育植物，
that makes it grow faster.
让它长得更快。
Or maybe you have bigger carrots than normal, bigger potatoes because they're super grown.
或者你可能会得到比正常更大的胡萝卜、更大的土豆，因为它们是被超级培育的。
That's right. So, all right. That's a lot of great stuff. Let's take a listen to the
没错。好了，这有很多精彩的内容。让我们最后再听一遍
dialogue one last time.
对话。
Have you read all these crazy things that are going on around the world?
你读过世界上发生的所有这些疯狂的事情吗？
What do you mean?
你指的是什么？
I was reading about how some people get tricked or drugged in their hotel rooms and have their
我读到一些人在酒店房间里被骗或下药，然后他们的
organs removed. Then they're sold on the black market.
器官被摘除，并在黑市上出售。
Don't tell me you actually believe all that. Don't be so gullible. They are just urban
别告诉我你真的相信这些。别这么容易上当。它们只是都市
legends. They're just stories people make up to scare you.
传说。只是人们编出来吓唬你的故事。
Well, I was also reading about how some popular songs have subliminal or even satanic messages
嗯，我还读到一些流行歌曲如果倒着播放，会有潜意识甚至撒旦的信息。
if you play them backwards. Can you believe that?
你能相信吗？
You really think an artist or songwriter is going to go through the trouble of putting
你真的认为一个艺术家或词曲作者会费尽心思在歌曲里加入
subliminal or satanic messages in a song? Don't be so naive.
潜意识或撒旦的信息吗？别这么天真了。
Well, maybe you are right. But how about the story about how KFC has rows of headless chickens
嗯，也许你是对的。但关于肯德基有一排排无头鸡，
which are super grown in order to get bigger chickens faster?
为了更快地得到更大的鸡而被超级培育的故事呢？
Sounds a bit too far-fetched to be true, don't you think?
听起来有点太牵强了，不像是真的，你不觉得吗？
All right. So, all these urban legends, they are obviously most of them, if not all of
好了。所以，所有这些都市传说，显然大部分，如果不是全部的话，
them, are untrue. But they're very popular. Why do you think that is?
都是不真实的。但它们很流行。你觉得这是为什么？
I think people like to believe these stories. They're gossipy. They're scary. You get to
我觉得人们喜欢相信这些故事。它们很八卦，很吓人。你可以
make your friends kind of nervous about stuff. But I think also we don't trust a lot of these
让你的朋友对某些事情感到紧张。但我也认为我们不信任很多这些
things because we've heard for years and years and years and years about subliminal messages
东西，因为我们年复一年地听到关于潜意识信息
and marketing strategies or about these kind of hidden messages in songs. So, there's part
和营销策略，或者歌曲中这些隐藏信息的故事。所以，我们有一部分
of us that wants to believe them. But the other part is that you hear it enough, you
人想要相信它们。但另一部分是，你听得足够多，
start to believe it.
就开始相信了。
Because I was reading up on a couple of them and the most recent ones are about how they
因为我查了一些，最近的一些是关于他们如何
make the connection about how Nostradamus predicted the 9-11 incident or how Coca-Cola
将诺查丹玛斯预言911事件联系起来，或者可口可乐
is actually the one that invented Santa Claus. And even this KFC one where people just believe
实际上是发明圣诞老人的公司。甚至这个肯德基的故事，人们就是相信
a lot of different things. I even found one, the urban legend about be careful when you
很多不同的东西。我甚至发现了一个都市传说，关于去电影院时要小心，
go to the movie theater because there might be a syringe or something on the seat that
因为座位上可能有注射器之类的东西，
if you sit down it infects you with AIDS or something like this. So, there's so many of
如果你坐下，它会让你感染艾滋病之类的。所以，有这么多
them out there that if you think about it, they don't even really make sense.
这样的故事，如果你仔细想想，它们甚至根本说不通。
They don't. And I understand that sometimes there'll be one news story like about a needle
确实说不通。我明白有时候会有一个新闻故事，比如糖果盒里有针。
in a candy box. And all of a sudden people say, well, don't eat candy because there's
然后突然人们就说，嗯，别吃糖果了，因为
needles in candy boxes.
糖果盒里有针。
And obviously, one time event turns into this massive kind of craze.
显然，一次事件就变成了这种大规模的狂热。
Yeah. But it is interesting, especially with this whole topic of subliminal messages. I
是啊。但这很有趣，尤其是关于潜意识信息这个主题。我
do remember that actually there was a marketing campaign that was banned in movie theaters
确实记得，实际上有一个营销活动在电影院被禁止了，
when the previews before the actual movie came on. Supposedly, they had the sound or
当时是在正片前的预告片播放时。据说，他们有声音或者
maybe on the screen somebody opening up a Coke can and the smell of Coke actually coming
可能在屏幕上有人打开一罐可乐，然后可乐的味道真的
into the theater. And that was kind of like subliminal marketing making people want to
飘进影院。这有点像潜意识营销，让人们想
go get a Coke.
去买可乐。
Definitely. Well, we used to pump the exhaust from the popcorn maker when I worked in a
确实。嗯，我在电影院工作时，我们曾经把爆米花机的排气
movie theater throughout the lobby. So, everyone smells it and it smells so good. Everyone
抽到整个大厅。所以每个人都能闻到，味道很好。每个人
wants to buy it.
都想买。
You want to buy popcorn?
你想买爆米花吗？
Oh, yeah. We would totally use that.
哦，是的。我们完全会利用这一点。
So, yeah. That is a way of like, I guess it is subliminal because you're not directly
所以，是的。这是一种方式，我想这算是潜意识，因为你没有直接
telling them to buy it, but you are just giving them all the...
告诉他们去买，但你只是给了他们所有的...
Adjusting it through audio or visual or oratory cues.
通过听觉、视觉或口头的暗示来调整。
Right. And then you have the opportunity to sell them the most expensive popcorn they'll
对。然后你就有机会卖给他们最贵的爆米花，
ever buy.
他们可能买过的最贵的。
Exactly. Twelve dollars for a bag of popcorn.
没错。一袋爆米花十二美元。
All right. So, it is a very interesting topic. Let us know if you have any comments or questions
好了。这是一个非常有趣的话题。如果你有任何评论或问题，
about it. You can find us at EnglishPod.com.
请告诉我们。你可以在EnglishPod.com找到我们。
We hope to see you guys there. Bye.
我们希望能在那里见到你们。再见。
Bye.
再见。